Diego A. Pérez Parés

diegodevelops@gmail.com (787) 415-6750 www.linkedin.com/in/diego-perez-961bb4115

Summary

Software Engineer from San Juan, Puerto Rico, with over six years of experience. Open to any new challenge and constantly learning. Skills and regularly used tools include: Swift, NodeJS, Typescript, ReactJS, Firebase, MongoDB and API integration.

Work Experience

Independent & Contract iOS and Web Developer

2018 - Present

- CommentExtractor Currently maintain and develop iOS app and backend for Instagram users to help make giveaways and other comment related tasks easier. Has over a thousand monthly active users. Uses: in-app purchases and Firebase for backend. https://commentextractor.com
- Moy Studio Currently maintain and develop website for local and online fashion school built with NextJS and Typescript. Improved SEO by using Chrome Lighthouse and following best UI practices. Features include online appointment and payment processing using Stripe. https://moystudiopr.com

Body Temple, Freelance Fullstack and Mobile Developer

2018 - 2022

Lead developer on Web, iOS and Android apps for local gym located in San Juan, Puerto Rico.
Created features like online appointments, QR code scanning, payment processing and push notifications. https://bodytemplepr.com

Software Developer, Triple-S

2019 - 2021

- Joined team of eight developers to work on development of in-house web platform for the different company roles within the property insurance sector
- · Help re-launch their iOS application
- Evaluated customer needs and feedback to drive product and service improvements

Jr. Software Developer, Soluwise

2017 - 2018

- Joined a small team of developers in a local telecom company
- Improved team workflows by creating Perl scripts and integrating with system APIs
- Optimized bulk SMS campaigns by developing an in-house Android app
- Worked on iOS app. https://apps.apple.com/us/app/cine/id375973809

Education

Udacity

Certificate in iOS Development Certificate in Full Stack JavaScript Development

Polytechnic University of Puerto Rico

B.S. in Mechanical Engineering, 2016